《越狱》  前情回顾
Previously on Prison Break.
如果"锡拉"是一张饼  我们只拿到其中一块
If Scylla was like a pizza, all we got is a slice.
"锡拉"不是一张卡
So Scylla isn't one card.
是六张
It's six.
这事发生多久了
How long has  it been happening?
这不是大问题
It's not a big deal.
你13岁的时候  就已是个大问题了
It was a big deal when you were 13.
迈克尔和你说过妈的事吗
Michael told you about Mom?
-没有  -她小时候经常流鼻血
No. As a kid, she got nosebleeds.
她30多岁时  又开始流鼻血
In her 30s, they started up again.
你母亲什么时候去世的
How old was your mom when she passed away?
31岁  迈克尔也刚好31岁
31. Michael's just turning 31.
那个人是谁
Who's that?
他就是杀我儿子的凶手
That's the man that killed my son.
他就象个数码黑洞
It's like a digital black hole.
能接收10英尺内的所有电子数据
It swallows up any electronic data within ten feet.
格兰先生
Mr. Glenn?
我们有麻烦了
We got a problem.
那是干什么用的
What's that do?
是个电子游戏机的
It's a battery pack
电池组
for a video game console.
那你只能买个新的了
You'll need to buy a new one.
锡拉  明天给我的话
Scylla. Get it to me by tomorrow
你就能拿原来报酬的一半
and you will receive 50% of the fee.
后天  四分之一
Two days, 25%.
大后天
Three days,
我让你脑袋开花
I shoot you through the brain.
你是谁
Who is this?
你好  迈克尔
Hello, Michael.
你明白吧
You know what?
如果格莱布再给我找这样的烂活
If Crab ever throws a psycho at us like this again,
我就宰了他
I'm going to kill him.
对  但是我们如果不干的话  格莱布会宰了我们
Yeah, but if we don't get this psycho, Crab's going to kill us.
把枪准备好
Just have the burner ready.
准备好了
Got it covered.
做完这个之后  我就洗手不干了
After this job, I'm done, man.
我不能再做下去了
I can't do this anymore.
你觉得格莱布会怎么说
What do you think Crab will say about that?
我不管他说什么
I don't care what Crab says about that.
如果进监狱的话  我还怎么做个好父亲
How can I be a good father if I'm always in prison?
我错过了我孩子的童年
I missed out on my kid's childhood.
我不能再错过他成长的过程
I'm not going to miss out on him becoming a man.
说实话  就算是你干  这个计划也太大胆了
You know, not for nothing, but this plan is crazy even for you.
你确定这是唯一办法
You sure this is the only way?
没错
Yeah.
快看  他出来了
Hey look. He's coming out.
他带着箱子
He's got the case.
系好安全带
Let's buckle up.
把手举起来  把手举起来
Put your hands up! Put your hands up!
别客气
You're welcome.
快闪
Let's go!
等等  这就是你的好主意
So wait a minute. This is your brilliant plan?
你打算用自杀的方法去撞将军的车
You're going to pull a kamikaze mission on the General's car?
你的仪器已经没了
Now that the device is gone,
你的意见也就不重要了
your opinion doesn't matter.
闭嘴  加你的油
So shut up and pump.
我们知道将军总是轻装行动
We know the General travels light.
一辆轿车  几个保镖
One limo and a couple of guards.
我不担心那几个保镖  我担心的是撞车
It ain't the guards I'm worried about; it's the crash.
我没说过这会很轻松
Look, I never said this was going to be easy.
别激动
Just relax.
首先  巴拿马的事是公事公办
First off, Panama was a job.
日后再算账
Some other time.
你要“锡拉“做什么
What do you want with Scylla?
那是我自己的事
That's my business.
我们不是在巴拿马
We're not in Panama anymore,
我也不在监狱里  我再问一次
and I'm not behind a fence, so, again,
你要“锡拉”做什么
what do you want with Scylla?
和你一样  打垮公司
Same thing you want: bring down the Company.
很好  那你何不
Great. Then why don't you
把缺的几页纸给我  然后消失呢
give me those missing pages and disappear?
我很想那么做  你记得那天
I'd love to. You remember that day
我们在罗斯福酒店  惠斯勒复制了Lief的卡
at the Roosevelt when Whistler made off with Lief's card?
你觉得是谁的主意
Who do you think took the fall for that?
我们的名字都在同一张黑名单里
Our names are at the top of the same hit list.
我不知道你们有什么协议
Now, I don't know what arrangement you two have,
我需要一些资金
but I need some traveling money.
我们过会再谈这个
Let's talk about that later.
我们干嘛不谈谈你是在给
Why don't we talk about the kind of scum
什么样的烂人付钱
you're willing to put on the payroll?
告诉我一个用不到她的理由  我听你的
Give me a way to do it without her, and we'll do it.
我们需要那些纸
We need the pages.
这是个交易
It's a package deal.
我们是拍档了吗
Are we partners?
拍档
Partners.
我刚刚往机器里投了一个币
Look, I barely dropped a nickel in the slots, right?
那人就过来了
This guy was all...
我们真应该打死你
We ought to blanket party your ass.
那个仪器呢
Where's the device?
-能不能拿回来  -快说
Can it be salvaged? Tell him.
赌台老板把它收走了
Pit boss walked off with it.
那好  我们只能让你提前退休了
Okay. Well, we're going to call this your early retirement.
你要么上楼
You can either go upstairs
坐在你的小床上  等我们把事情解决
and sit on your cot and ride out the rest of this thing,
否则  我就给赛尔夫探员打电话
or I can call Agent Self
那你就能慢慢享受刑期了
and you can ride out the rest of your prison sentence.
你选吧
Your choice.
我要和你谈谈
I need to talk to you.
你哥哥说了你流鼻血的事
So your brother told me about your nosebleeds.
他还说了你妈妈的情况
And he told me about your mom.
那不是他该做的
That wasn't his place.
为你担心
To be worried about you?
妈妈得病时  林肯每天都在医院  握着她的手
When Mom got sick, Linc was at the hospital every day, holding her hand,
看着妈妈去世  他那时才13岁
watching her die, and he was 13.
这件事改变了他  让他对任何事都过头担心
It changed him. It made him overprotective.
现在他开始
And now he's jumping
用错误的原因
to all the wrong conclusions
得出错误的结论
for all the wrong reasons,
而且都无中生有的
and it's... it's over nothing because
我很好
I'm fine.
你看起来可不好
You don't look fine.
因为我也有些事情要告诉你
Well, maybe that's because there's something I have to tell you.
格雷琴还活着
Gretchen's alive.
本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
更多字幕下载 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
字幕：YYeTs人人影视字幕组  后期：zwzy_1007(胖胖)
《越狱》第四季 第八集
Prison.Break.S04E08
她和帝博格一起合作
She's working with T-Bag,
他们有几张惠斯勒的鸟类书页
and they have several pages from Whistler's bird book,
他们也想加入找锡拉
and they want in on Scylla.
我们说话的同时  赛尔夫正和他们谈条件
Self is cutting them a deal as we speak.
赛尔夫知道他们有自己的计划
Self knows that they have their own agenda,
但我们也有
but so do we
只要我们拿到那几页纸
and as soon as we get those pages back,
格雷琴和帝博格就会为他们做的事付出代价
Gretchen and T-Bag are going to pay for everything.
他们会得到应有的惩罚
They're going to get exactly what's coming to them.
整件事情和格雷琴无关
This isn't about Gretchen.
也不会牵扯私人恩怨
It's not about any one person.
我们必须结束这一切
And we... we have to finish it.
我想自己呆一会
I need a minute.
可以吗
Please.
我绝对不相信
I can't believe this!
我们有其他选择吗
What choice do we have?
格雷琴加入我们
Gretchen's on the team.
不管喜不喜欢
Like it or not,
我们需要那几页纸
we need those pages.
我们要和这婊子[西班牙语]合作
Another perra we're jumping in bed with?
对我们来说不是第一次了
Not exactly new territory for us.
我不管我们要和谁合作
I don't care who we gotta partner up with.
我们拿到那些纸  就才可以打入"公司"
We get those papers, we make with the break-in,
就能完成任务
we get this job done.
她也可能和"公司"还有联系  我不确定
She could still have ties to the Company, man. I don't know.
到时候  我们再担心格雷琴
We'll worry about Gretchen when the time is right.
现在  我们要集中在将军身上
For now, let's focus on the General.
格雷琴加入我们也改变不了什么
This thing with Gretchen doesn't change a thing.
我们
We're, uh...
我们还是接近目标
we're still close.
更接近"锡拉"  离怀特却更远了
Closer to Scylla, farther from Wyatt.
这也说不准
You don't know that.
先集中精力  好吗
Just stay focused, all right?
这才是我要集中精力的地方
This is my focus, okay?
我还是做我该做的事
I'm doing the job, okay? All right? All right?
每一天  杀我儿子的凶手就离我更远
Every day, the trail to my son's killer gets a little bit colder.
我能做的就只有集中精力
That's all I do is focus.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
只是
Um... It's just... uh...
我们要把电脑拿楼下用
We're going to need that downstairs.
那我就呆在这好了
Yeah. I'll just, uh... be up here.
多少钱换斯科菲尔德和布伦斯
How much for Scofield and Burrows?
我听说你们俩有了个协议
I see you two have come to an agreement.
放了她 是因为她要工作
She's on work release,
和你一样
just like you.
什么样的工作
What kind of work?
你和那个秘书在办公室里保守秘密
You and the secretary keep things quiet in the office
迈克尔从隧道去找"锡拉"
while Michael tunnels to Scylla.
你真的以为
You really think
斯科菲尔德会遵守他的诺言
Scofield's gonna keep his word, huh?
你把他爱的女人往死里打
You horsewhipped the woman he loves.
迈克尔和我们一样想得到“锡拉”
Michael wants Scylla just as badly as we do.
没错  他当时也想逃出监狱
Yeah, he wanted out of prison, too.
我们的合作在那之后就结束了
Our partnership lasted long enough for that to happen,
然后  我们就分道扬镳了
and then...  we parted ways.
相信我
Trust me.
先生  请进
Yeah, um, go on in, sir.
斯科菲尔德会利用你
Scofield will use you
为了给他女朋友报仇  他会在你背后来一刀
and then he's gonna bury the knife in your back for what you did to his lady friend.
"锡拉"在哪
Where's Scylla?
早上好  先生
Good morning to you, too, sir.
先生们
Gentlemen.
我给了你3天
I gave you three days.
"锡拉"在哪
Where's Scylla?
我
I...
冯先生  别急着下结论
Now, uh, Mr. Feng, let's not do anything rash.
你就是冯
So you're Feng.
我们还没见过面
We haven't actually met in person.
我就是"斑蛇行动"中
I was the liaison between the Company and your
你的雇主和"公司"之间的联络人
Chinese employers on Operation Copperhead.
苏珊
Susan?
没错
That's right.
你从为"公司"卖命
You went from working for the Company
转变为盗取能摧毁他们的证据
to stealing the one thing that could destroy them.
这个转变未免太突然了
That's a tight turn.
从"锡拉"的价格来看
With a price that Scylla commands on the open market,
任何人都会变
anybody would turn.
顺便说一下  值200吧
Which is, by the way, 200.
我们在行动中没有合作过
Our paths never crossed on Copperhead,
但是我确实和你的一个同事合作过
but I did deal with one of your colleagues;
一个不太能干的中间人
a less-capable associate.
他怎么了
Whatever happened to him?
他已经从这个世界消失了
He was skinned and hung from an overpass.
我想起来了
Oh, yes, I recall.
他没有在保证的时间内把东西送到
He couldn't deliver on promises made.
你也可能会想起  他是我的前任
You may also recall that he was my predecessor.
我参加行动后  你得到了你想要的
When I joined Copperhead, you got what you wanted.
我也会得到"锡拉"
You'll get Scylla, too.
如果我拿不到
If I don't,
我就扒了你的皮
I'll peel you like a wet grape.
报酬是100
And the price is 100.
150.
125  别让我失望
125. Don't disappoint me.
你们说的  125
Well, 125...
再乘1百万
Million.
苏珊  格雷琴  不管你名字是什么
Susan, Gretchen, whatever your name is,
我建议你赶快找个方法
I suggest you find a way to bury the hatchet
和迈克尔·斯科菲尔德的女人和解
with Michael Scofield's woman.
我们有的忙了
We got work to do.
我怎么觉得有人早上起来
Why do I get the feeling that some poor bastard woke up
会发现自己的车没了
to an empty driveway this morning?
放松  我们从回收厂找来的
Relax, we got it from a scrap yard.
你们准备就寄望于
And you're pinning the hopes
这堆废铁吗
of the entire mission on that relic?
如果是第一张卡  我不会这么做
If it was card one, I'd say no.
如果是第五张
If this was card five,
我也不会这么做  但这是最后一张
I'd say no, but it's the last card.
我觉得可以假装肇事逃逸
I really think we can stage a hit-and-run
没有人会关注这件事
and get away with it.
好吧  我们知道他在哪上班
All right, we know where this guy works.
我们也知道他的路线
We know his route.
我会在这个十字路口等他
I'm gonna wait for him at this intersection.
他开过来
He drives through.
我开车撞他  拿到卡
I smash him with my car, get the card.
如果你能奇迹般活着离开现场
And if by some miracle you walked away from the crash,
将军就会知道是你偷了卡
the General's gonna know that you ripped him off.
除非我先给他打一针吗啡
Not if I pump him full of morphine first.
将军会第二天在医院醒过来
The General's gonna wake up tomorrow morning in the hospital
一点也不记得到底发生了什么事情
feeling happy as a clam with no idea what happened to him.
当他不省人事的时候
When he's out cold,
我们把卡下载到手提电脑里
we download the card onto the laptop
再把原卡放回去
and put the original back on him.
你以为救护人员来了
And you don't think this is gonna look suspicious
不会怀疑吗
for the paramedics that show up at the scene?
那就要看急救人员是谁了
That depends on who the paramedics are.
现在有四辆救护车
At the federal impound lot downtown,
因走私药品
there are currently four ambulances seized
被扣押在市中心的车管所
in a drug-smuggling ring.
我们只需要一辆
All we need is one.
你去搞定吧
Go make yourself useful.
指挥官会在作战前集结军队
Time was commanders would assemble their troops
并在方形土阵中做排练
before a battle and rehearse schemes of maneuver
用石头代指敌方地点
on a square of dirt using rocks to depict enemy positions.
他们称之为  "划石作战"
They called these rehearsals "rock drills."
老挝就是我们的石头  现在...
Laos was our rock drill. Now...
现在已经箭在弦上了
it's time for the battle to commence.
格里芬
Griffin.
用伪钞冲刷老挝市场
Flooding the Laotian market with counterfeit kip
非常有效
was highly effective.
到第二阶段  影响将继续扩大
In Phase Two, the effect will take longer,
但结果必然如出一辙
but the result will inevitably be the same.
我正在停止该命令
I'm signing off on the order to open up
以打开下一战区
the next theater of operations.
失陪
Excuse me.
信息来源很难摸透
The message is untraceable.
某人花了很多功夫
Someone went to a lot of trouble
去掩盖他们的踪迹
to cover their tracks.
你怎么知道此人能帮我们找到这两兄弟
How do we know this person can deliver the brothers?
我们不知道
We don't.
引蛇出洞
Bait the hook.
看他会不会上钩
See if he bites.
你好  朋友
Hey-hey, my friend!
你是谁
Who the hell are you?
唐·赛尔夫  国土安全局的
Don Self, Homeland Security.
菲尔·斯托格尔
Phil Stroger.
最近怎么样 不错
How's it going? Good.
这可是好东西
This is a grande.
这东西花了我9美金
This thing cost me nine bucks.
正和你加州口味  还有你的极品咖啡
You California types and your gourmet coffee.
我能为你做些什么
Hey, can I help you with something?
这是市车管所  对吗
This is a federal impound lot, correct?
没错
Yeah.
我的意图很明显  菲尔  我需要一辆车
Okay, I think it's pretty obvious, Phil, I need a car.
你告诉莎拉我流鼻血的事
So you told Sara about the nosebleeds, huh?
我很担心你
I'm worried about you.
你为什么
Well, why don't you stop
哪壶不开提哪壶
starting fires that I have to put out?
妈妈都没能逃脱病魔  你以为你...
Mom couldn't outrun this. What makes you think you...?
这和妈妈的情况不一样  那是20年前的事
It's not Mom, all right? That was 20 years ago.
这不一样  完全不一样
This is different. It's totally different.
上车
Get in.
我的头头来视察菜鸟们的宿舍
So my section chief comes over to the rookie's stretcher
然后他说  你们的补贴还真不少啊  孩子
and he goes, "You got one hell of a workman's comp claim, kid."
兄弟 我们说正事吧
Hey, uh, let's get that trip ticket started.
看来我能帮你
Looks like I can hook you up
弄辆轿车
with a sedan for your stakeout.
菲尔  我得走了
You know what, Phil? I gotta go.
说什么呢
What are you talking about?
我刚想起来
I just remembered.
我还得给上头们交份文件
I got to give a briefing to a bunch of higher-ups.
我还能回来
Can I come back
再拿车吗
for the sedan?
随你便  赛尔夫
Suit yourself, Self.
我一会回来
I'll be back.
唐·赛尔夫
Don Self.
我要你帮我传个口信
I need you to deliver a message.
好
Okay.
看来你男朋友不用再享受
I see your boyfriend's no longer sporting
最新的全球定位科技了
the latest fashion in GPS technology.
既然你们都不用戴脚踝监视器
So, if neither one of you are wearing ankle monitors,
你们还在这干嘛
what are you still doing here?
你们应该从这里到墨西哥
You should be having hot fugitive sex
找所有仅付现钞的汽车旅馆
in every cash only no-tell motel
去享受逃往的性爱
from here to Mexico.
比起俩人的需要
Some things are more important
还有更重要的事情  罗兰
than what two people want, Roland.
我真的希望有一天你会有所领悟
I honestly hope that someday that makes sense to you.
莎拉
Look, Sara...
对不起
I'm sorry.
维加斯的事
For Vegas.
我为维加斯发生的事道歉
I'm sorry for Vegas.
喂
Hello?
格雷琴给你捎了个口信
Listen, I have a message for you from Gretchen.
她想在今晚7点见你
She wants to meet with you tonight at 7:00 p.m.
在瑟法丽旅馆
at the Safari Motel
-109房  -为什么
on 109. Why?
她说想消除误会
She says she wants to clear the air,
不知道什么意思
whatever that means.
莎拉
Sara?
我没兴趣
I'm not interested.
好吧
Okay.
我有不祥的预感
I got a bad feeling about this.
我才是命悬一线的人  你只是待在救护车里
I'm the one on point. You're in the ambulance.
你担心什么
Why are you so worried?
我只是有这种感觉
I just got a feeling.
如果发生意外
If anything should happen,
帮我打电话给芝加哥的老妈
call my mom in Chicago.
告诉她我没有死于牢狱之灾
Tell her I didn't die like a damn convict
没有关在监狱里
locked up in some penitentiary.
不会有事的
Nothing's gonna happen.
准备好了吗
You ready for this?
好了  我和苏克雷能搞定
Yeah. Me and Sucre got this.
我知道你能行
I know you do.
祝好运
Good luck.
1百万  换俩兄弟  今天
1 million for the brothers today.
成交
Done.
一切就位
I'm in position.
好
Good.
我们在交叉路口
The rest of us are standing by
准备就绪
at the intersection.
没人希望你
No one's expecting you
真的去治疗这个混账家伙
to actually treat this bastard, right?
是  但我还是个医生
Yeah, I'm still a doctor.
苏克雷  你们那边情况怎样
Sucre, how you guys doing?
苏克雷
Sucre?
老天你不是在耍我吧
Got to be kidding me.
苏克雷  在吗
Sucre, are you there?
我们准备好了
We're good.
看来我成了惠斯勒先生
Being as I was the original recipient
艺术品的接收者
of the late Mr. Whistler's artwork...
我能拿多少
what's my cut?
2500万
$25 million.
如你所知
Just so you know,
我占有欲很强
I have a very keen sense of ownership.
库沙公墓
Six headstones
的六座墓碑就是明证
in Coosa County Cemetery can attest to that fact.
墓碑上的名字
The names on those grave markers
花了六箱在河里冷却的舒力茨[啤酒]
took a six pack of Schlitz I had cooling in the river.
那次犯罪我才得到五块钱
That particular transgression put me back five bucks.
想象为了2500万我会做什么
Imagine what I'd do for $25 million.
你会拿到钱
You'll get your cut.
但要靠你自己去挣
But you're gonna earn it.
斯科菲尔德和他的同伙
And how much of that payday
又能拿到多少
is Scofield and his crew earning?
我怀疑他们有没有命来拿
Oh, I doubt they'll be around to collect.
死那么多人
There's a lot of blood being spilled
花那么多钱
and a lot of money being
就为了本小破黑皮书
offered up for just a little old black book.
有什么好笑的
What's so funny?
人人都认为锡拉
That everyone thinks that Scylla
只是"公司"的小黑名单
is just the Company's little black book.
我怎么知道能否相信你
How do i know i can trust you?
现在去帝王大道和威洛斯大道
King and Willow Now.
小家伙
Hey, buddy.
从林肯那里得知  你母亲的右额叶上
I understand from Lincoln your mom had a hamartoma
长了个错构瘤
in her right frontal lobe.
是的
That's right.
那种肿瘤增大后会造成困扰
When a tumor like that gets large enough to be problematic,
还会伴随很多症状
it's gonna come with a lot of symptoms.
短暂性失忆
Loss of short-term memory,
影响你的深度知觉
problems with your depth perception,
影响运动机能
problems with your motor skills.
如果你有以上症状
If you had anything like that,
-告诉我  -好的  但我没有
you'd let me know. Yes, but I haven't.
我也不会
And I won't.
我没事
And I'm fine.
2IBA333
迈克
Michael.
将军要走了
The General is leaving.
好的  大家就绪
All right, everybody get ready.
你没事吧
You doing all right?
没事  只是不习惯到处是血
Fine. Just not so good around blood is all.
我来处理好了
I'll take care of the messy part,
你只要帮我把他弄上轮床
you just help me get him on the gurney.
不用两个人去撞一辆车
Doesn't take two people to crash a car, you know.
你开玩笑吧
You're kidding me, right?
我们可曾共患难
After all I've been through with you?
现在你倒担心我了
Now you're worried about my ass?
闭嘴  开车
Shut up and drive, okay?
系好安全带
Buckle up.
什么事
What is it?
林肯  我们看到他了  离你们两条街远
Linc, we got him. He's two blocks away from you.
我们准备好了
We're on it.
开始了
Here we go.
他在做什么
What's he doing?
不对劲
Something's wrong.
他掉头了
He's turning around.
林肯  撤退  是陷阱
Linc, pull back! It's a trap.
我们快闪
Let's get out of here.
苏克雷  趴下
Sucre, get down!
林肯  快点
Come on, Linc!
开快点
Faster!
低下头
Keep your head down!
抓紧
Hang on!
你没事吧
You all right?!
费尔南多  坚持住  你会没事的
Stay with us, Fernando. You're going to be all right.
他直接冲过来  我们中埋伏了
He came straight at us. We were set up.
你是说他们知道我们会去那
So you're saying that they knew we were going to be there?
-那他们也知道这地方了  -我也这么说
Then they know about this place. That's exactly what I'm saying.
-布拉德  我要纱布  -随时会有人过来的
Brad, I'm gonna need some gauze. Somebody could be coming here right now.
如果他们知道这地方  那我们早就死了
If they knew about this place, we'd already be dead.
那个格雷琴呢
What about that Gretchen chick?
她有惠斯勒的几张书页
She's got a couple of pages from Whistler's bird book.
她不可能知道
It doesn't make her psychic.
布拉德  我需要纱布
Brad, I need some gauze.
现在相信我了吧
Trust me now?
看来有人出卖我们了
Well, it looks like someone set us up.
-真的吗  -是的
Seriously? Yeah.
我在想是不是你
And I'm wondering if it was you.
你们起初是排斥我
Okay, first you give me the leper treatment,
现在又说我是告密者
and now I'm a traitor
-是吗  -的了吧  罗兰
is that right? Come on, Roland, who else
除了你还有谁知道我们
could've known we were going
-要去那个交叉口  -告诉你
at that intersection? You know what, just because
别因为我没跟你们一起行动  就说我是告密者
I didn't do time with you guys, it doesn't make me a rat.
对此我的投入
All right? I put just as much into this job
不比任何人少
as anybody else.
就算我犯了个小错
Okay, I make one little mistake
我就成犹大了吗
and all of a sudden I'm Judas?
不  算了
No, you know what? You know, no.
打电话给Self  我回
Call Self, okay, because... because I'm gonna go back
-监狱去  -好了
to the can. I'm done with this... All right.
冷静点  冷静点
Just calm down. Calm down.
我要你查一下
I want you to look up
帝王大道和威洛斯大道街角的
all the local businesses at the corner
所有地方企业
of King and Willow.
我要外部装有安全摄像的
I need the ones with exterior security cameras,
因为我要查个车牌号
'cause I'm looking for a license plate number,
好吗
all right?
为什么不道歉
How about an apology?
斯科菲尔德去哪了
Where the hell is Scofield?
我们全等着他破土动工
We've been waiting for him to break ground all day.
他还要处理最后一件事
He's taking care of one last thing.
早上他会来找你
He'll be here in the morning.
莎拉呢  她对会面作何回应
And Sara, what'd she say about our meeting?
她说没兴趣
She's not interested.
行  如果她改变注意  我会在那等她
Okay, well, if she changes her mind, I'll be there.
只想让大家都知道
Just so everyone knows,
这是莎拉做了结的最后机会
this is Sara's last chance to settle up.
我想让大家开诚布公
I want all the grievances out on the table
这样我们才能继续合作
so we can move forward.
听清楚了  美女
Listen to me, skank.
你只是被
You just got your stripes
你的旧老板甩掉的鸟人
ripped off your sleeve by your old boss.
不管以前你在公司里的官多大
So whatever clout you had with the Company,
现在都没了
it's gone.
你现在是我的手下
You work for me now.
所以  你在这个乡巴佬面前怎么摆架子都行
So you can try to pull rank on the hick here all you want,
但别把我的耐心当弱点
but don't mistake my patience for weakness.
你还活着只有一个理由
You're alive right now for one reason:
就是我允许你活着
because I'm allowing you to be.
一旦把锡拉弄到手
So when I get Scylla,
你就可以拿到你的报酬
you'll get your traveling money.
而这一切都结束后
And when this is over,
你要是胆敢踏进
if you step one foot
美国半步  我会用
on American soil, I'm gonna take
这把枪...
this gun...
用子弹在你这里
and I'm gonna put a bullet
开个洞
right there.
你也一样  乡巴佬
And that goes for you, too, Gummo.
听清楚了吗
Are we clear?
听清楚了
We're clear.
给  我做的
Here. I made this.
这个图表记录了
It's a chart of all
所以进出这个办公室的人
the people coming in and out of the office,
显示了哪天  什么时段是最忙的
showing which times of the day are the busiest
以及什么时段可以挖掘
and which are best for digging.
只管听电话就行
Just answer the phones.
我会处理这个
I'll handle this.
-拿到了吗  -等等
- Did you get it? - Hold on.
赶快
Hurry up.
为什么要
Why are we doing
再做一次
this again?
如果她想不付锡拉的账
It's an insurance policy.
这就是我们的救命稻草
If she tries to get out of that big Scylla payday.
有多少钱
How big of a payday?
1百万美元
One million dollars.
你如果再用枪指着我
You put a gun on me again,
我就不会单单会把她的指纹复制下来
and these aren't the only set of prints I'll be copying.
从现在开始  我们是盟友了
From this moment on, we are allies.
她还在看我们吗
She watching?
是的
Yes.
撑着点
Brace yourself.
干嘛
For what?
没叫你  以后不准再踏进我办公室半步
Don't you ever come in my office again unless you're summoned!
布伦斯在车上
Burrows was in the car.
看来情报是可靠的
It appears our source is dependable.
我说引蛇出洞  可不意味着用我做饵
When I said bait the hook, I did not mean with me.
他们差一点就杀了我
They came that close to killing me.
我不会让这种事情发生
I wouldn't let that happen.
如果你不满意我的方法
But if you're unhappy with my methods,
你大可以让别人来做
maybe you should parcel out the job to someone else.
我不接受辞呈
I don't accept resignations.
和神秘人达成协议
Close the deal with the mystery man
今天就把俩兄弟给我抓回来
and bring the brothers to me today
否则你的解雇金就会变成运尸袋
or your severence pay will be a body bag.
光天化日  在大街上  他们知道你的路线
Broad daylight, city street, and they knew your route.
如果斯科菲尔德的任务是想杀你
If Scofield's mission was to kill you,
他会用更好的办法
he'd have a better way to do it.
-还要其他东西吗  -不用
Sara, you have everything you need? No.
没事
I'm good.
一切顺利  好了
Everything's just fine.Alright.
快好了  费尔南多
Almost done, Fernando.
可以了
Now you go.
医生  如果不是你的话 我就死在这桌子上了
I would've died on this table if it weren't for you, Doc.
我会等你付诊金的
Mm-hmm. Just wait till you get my bill.
撑着点  苏克雷
Hang in there, Sucre.
就算"公司"还不知道这个仓库
Even if the warehouse ain't on the Company's radar,
我们很清楚被发现后的结果
we sure as hell are.
-这事完了  -你说不准
This job's over. You don't know that.
我只知道  我不想回福克斯河监狱
I ain't going back to Fox River, I know that.
你觉得赛尔夫发现公司把我们弄成这样
What do you think Self is gonna do
他会怎么做
when he finds out the Company made us?
我们很快就会知道
We're about to find out.
喂
Yeah?
罗兰在哪
Hey, where the hell is Roland?
他的全球定位掉线了
His GPS just went offline.
我到了
I'm here.
怎样
Well?
开丰田走了
Took the Corolla.
-把他的手提也带了吗  -是的
Take his laptop, too? Yeah.
阿历克斯
Alex.
你还好吗
You doing okay?
-医生  还要多久  -快了
How much longer,doc? Almost.
你能处理这些吗
Hey, you got this covered?
你们还在这干什么
What are you still doing here?
去把那兔崽子抓回来
Go get the son of a bitch.
行了
All done.
把钱带来了吗
You got my money?
我以为这是
Oh, yo, I thought this
公平交易  对吧
was going to be a legit business transaction, okay?
你不给我钱  我就不会
You don't got my money, I don't got
-把俩兄弟的地址告诉你  -他们在哪
the location of the brothers. Where are they?
天啊
Oh, God!
你这是干什么
What are you doing?!
莎拉
Sara...
你好  莎拉
Hello, Sara.
我以前的一个导师给我讲过一个故事
A former mentor of mine once told me a story
我觉得很适合这个情况
that I think applies to this situation.
内战结束时  格兰特的联军
At the end of the Civil War, Grant's Union Army
在阿波马托克斯战胜李的联军
had Lee's Confederate soldiers outflanked at Appomattox.
李明白更多流血事件的无益
Lee understood the futility of more bloodshed,
所以他请求停战
so he requested a cease-fire.
他想结束战争
He wanted to bring an end to the fighting.
当天早上还在互相厮杀的士兵
Soldiers that had been killing each other that morning,
下午首次穿过战线
walked across the lines that afternoon
成为同盟
for the first time as allies
互相交换北方的咖啡和南方的烟草
to trade Northern coffee for Southern tobacco.
现在  我不期望我们互换礼品
Now, I don't expect us to exchange gifts,
但不意味着我们不能成为盟友
but that doesn't mean we can't be allies.
当然  你不会和解
Of course, you can't have a cease-fire
除非双方
without both parties
达到各自目的
getting what they want.
你有5分钟
You have five minutes.
随你尽管在我背上加伤疤
Put as many scars on my back as possible.
我不想催你  但只剩4分钟了
I don't want to rush you, but you have four minutes left.
她叫什么名字
What was her name?
只有这一次机会  莎拉
This is a one-time deal, Sara.
你要血债血还  现在就动手
You want your pound of flesh, you take it now.
-她叫什么名字  -谁
What was her name? Who?
看守的人
The guard--
你射杀  死在我怀里的人
the one you shot and left to die in my arms.
就为这个
That's what this is about?
一个不尽职的看守人
A guard that couldn't do her job?
她叫什么名字
What was her name?
泰勒
Taylor.
她的姓呢
Her first name?
米歇尔  我想
Michelle... I think.
你应该清楚  这不是为我
You should know that this isn't about me.
我能忍受你在我背上留的伤疤
I can handle the scars you put on my back,
但你对米歇尔的作为
but what you did to Michelle...
我得服从命令  她想帮你逃跑
I had orders. She tried to help you escape.
她帮我逃脱了  她不是想
She did help me escape. She didn't try.
莎拉
Sara...
你只想着用她来杀鸡儆猴
You were too busy making an example out of her
没想到找她留给我的钥匙
to find the key that she left with me.
她也得到应有的惩罚了
Then she got what she deserved.
她救了我
She saved my life.
而你杀了她
And you took her's.
你达到目的了
You proved your point.
我们扯平了
We're even.
我们还离扯平远着呢
We're a long way from even.
等这个结束了  你会为米歇尔付出代价
And when this is over, you'll pay for Michelle.
他们在哪
Where are they?
在膝盖骨上中一枪
The thing about a gunshot to the kneecap--
会过几天才能死
it takes days to die from it.
现在  如果说  我在这里
Now, if I were to shoot you, let's say,
开一枪
here...
弹头会直接穿过你的身体
the hollow point would tumble through you
在你的内脏留下炙热的裂片
leaving white-hot slivers in your insides,
带给你难以想象的痛苦
causing unimaginable pain.
直到你在这小道里流血而亡
Only ending when you bled out on this pavement.
你不想这样吧
You don't want that, do you?
告诉我他们兄弟在哪
Then tell me where the brothers are.
他们在一个仓库里
They're in a warehouse.
圣佩德罗30号码头  他们都在那
Pier 31, San Pedro-- they're all there.
-求你  -谢谢
Please... Thank you.
不
No!
你在干嘛
What are you doing?!
我说了你想知道的
I told you what you wanted...!
不  不
No, no...
不
No!
好了  好了
All right, all right!
你迟早有机会收拾他  退后
You'll get your shot. Now back off.
阿历克斯  听他的
Alex, listen to him.
你迟早有机会收拾他
Hey, hey, you'll get your shot, man.
You'll get your shot.
迈克尔  快走  他出卖了我们
Michael, come on. He sold us out.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
我们得走了
We got to go.
等等  等等
Wait... wait...
等等
Wait...
迈克尔  快走
Michael, let's go.
别再给我说什么新消息
Don't hand me any more updates.
他们在监视我了
They're surveilling me.
他们在追杀我
They're coming after me.
将军  我们会抓到他们的
General, we'll get them.
这又不是第一次
This isn't the first time someone's
有人想要你的命
made an attempt on your life.
这次不是想要我的命
This is not an attempt on my life.
这次是想得到我的卡
This is an attempt on my card.
叫怀特来
Get Wyatt.
我们正在联系他
We're trying to contact him.
别只关顾着想  快把怀特叫来
Don't try anything-- just get Wyatt.
你想怎么继续下去
How do you want to proceed?
我要转移它
I want it moved.
做必要的安全准备
To make the necessary arrangements for security
要好几天
would take days.
我不管有多困难
I don't care about logistics.
我要转移它
I want it moved.
转移锡拉
Move Scylla.
现在
Now!
对不起
I'm sorry...
对不起  对不起
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
我知道
I know.
我还不想死  兄弟
I'm not ready to go, man.